How are you, brother?
Where is your wife?
That's my wife.
There's a problem in the house.
That's very correct. That's why we are here.
When the two of you sit together, there is a big problem.
That's very correct, Prophet.
For the past three months now, this house has not been in order.
That's a hundred percent correct, Prophet!
It's like a cat and a rat living together.
One hundred percent. I can't say anymore.
You have to help this auntie. You have to help her.
Okay, Prophet.
You just have to help her.
So, don't use the family she comes from against her
because she comes from a disorganised family.
Okay, Prophet.
You are a prophet!
Thank you very much.
I want to see you.
Thank you.
Leaving this woman - it will affect you
because she is a woman that God has given you.
Thank you, Prophet.
You were bleeding in the past.
Yes, Prophet. That's very true.
What was the cause of the bleeding?
I have two fibroids in my womb.
Apart from fibroids.
I used to have an imbalance in my hormones so when the doctor tried to correct it, then --
Because I'm seeing bleeding, bleeding, bleeding.
Yes, it's very true.
I want to see you people - and you don't have affection for this woman.
It is not her that does not have affection; you don't have affection.
I don't know what the problem is, Prophet.
It's very true, Man of God; he doesn't have.
She loves you, she wants you, she wants to show love but you - you say, "Go and wait there!"
That's very true.
She has now turned to somebody you employed, not even your wife.
I think I need to see you.
Thank you very much, Prophet!
You're a nice man.
Thank you very much.
She's my mother-in-law, Prophet. She lives with us.
There is trouble in their house.
Don't worry. I have said it already.
You know the young people today - they don't want you to interfere in their family.
Thank you, Man of God!
Go and wait for me.
Everything will be alright.
My name is Chakoi.
I'm a Cameroonian by nationality but I live with my husband in Namibia.
This is my husband; his name is Helms.
This is my step-daughter, Emma.
This is my son, Helms Junior.
This is my mother, Katrine.
The prophecy that the man of God gave to us last Sunday was very true.
For the last three months, there have been serious problems in our house;
a lot of disagreements.
My husband asked me to pack my things and leave the house.
The problem we were having in the house was centred on my step-daughter,
the care of my step-daughter.
Actually, when my husband brought me to Namibia, everything was fine.
I came and met him in the house with a baby so I took the baby as my own baby.
So, as we were living and things were going on,
I finally discovered that there were things that were not very right in the life of this child.
Ok, before you go any further.
You were talking about a step-daughter. Could you tell us the daughter you are talking about?
This is my step-daughter; she is right here.
She is five years and about ten months old.
So, when I came and met her in Namibia, she just turned three.
Everything was fine until I started noticing some things in the child that are not correct.
The child was so unruly.
When I tried to put things right in the life of the child, it was very difficult.
Another thing that I noticed with the baby was that
the baby does not like for us to have prayers in the house,
she does not like the reading of the Bible, she does not like to go to church and all of that.
I was concerned about it and told my husband
that these things are not normal for a little baby like this.
So, I took her to several men of God for prayers.
They also confirmed to me that the baby was possessed.
So, they prayed for her and gave me anointing oil which I was using on the baby.
There were other attitudes in the child.
Nobody wants to bring up a child that is spoilt.
She was spoilt and the thing that marvelled me was how she talked at her age,
the way she would act and behave; it was not correct.
I tried to put things right; she was so unruly.
In the process of putting these things together,
my husband was seeing it as if I was not treating the child well.
As time went on, I came to discover that they segregated themselves from me.
When they were together, they were talking and laughing.
When I came close to them, they stayed quiet.
When they moved to another place and were talking, when I came, they would stay quiet.
When I left, they would start talking; when I came, they would stay quiet.
My presence was not really comfortable for them.
So I told them that I didn't have company in this house, I need company in the house.
If you people don't give me company, fine.
I will pray to God. When God will give me my own company, you people should not complain.
So you people should continue enjoying yourselves
but know that when God gives me my own company, nobody should complain.
In the course of time, I also had my own baby.
So when I shifted attention now to my own baby, my husband said that
I'm showing discrimination; there cannot be two children in the house
with one getting all the love, the other one not getting all the love.
I said, you are the ones that showed me that; you put me on one side.
So I don't have company; my company is here.
So let me enjoy my own company too.
Another issue of serious concern was that when I was about 4 months pregnant,
one morning --
I used to get up in the morning, prepare her and take her to school, and bring her back.
Even in the process of trying to make her become cultured because she was so uncultured.
She uses abusive language and all of that.
She does not hear this from us in the house so I tried to put things in order in her life.
One morning I was sick; I was not feeling fine.
So I got up; the housemaid prepared the baby.
She then told me, "The baby is ready. Please come and carry the baby to school".
I said, "Please, I'm very sick. Take taxi money and carry the baby to school".
She was taking the baby to school and told the baby, "We are going to school in a taxi".
The baby said, "There cannot be two cars" - I mean, at the age of four.
The baby said, "There cannot be two cars in my father's compound
and I'm going to school in a taxi.
Go and tell that woman to get out of that bed and take me to school".
The thing got on my nerves; I was like, what is this?
What kind of unruliness is this?
So I said, "As a point of discipline, you are only going to go to school in a taxi.
Your nanny will take you to school and bring you back from school
so that tomorrow when there is no car in the house, you will know that you have to take taxi".
My husband was seeing that as if I was maltreating the child, sending the child away from him.
All of these things came into play.
He was kind of wondering.
With the new baby, now I'm happy and rejoicing.
I look at my baby and smile.
Since the child is not comfortable in my presence, so she will also keep her own distance.
So the distance made my husband to become very uncomfortable.
Three months ago, he told me that my step-daughter was not happy
since she saw the baby entering the house.
That if I didn't make things right in the house,
with the baby not being comfortable in my presence, I should pack my things and leave
because he was not going to sit down and watch
and stay in a house where the wife is this way with her child, and the step-daughter this way.
He didn't know how to manage the situation
so the best thing was for me to pack my things and go.
So I said, "Okay, fine".
With the course of time, he decided to bring me to The SCOAN
so that the man of God should handle our case
because it was more than him; he didn't know what to do.
Ok. In the course of sharing your experience with us, you made us to understand
that it got to a state whereby you had to start taking your step-daughter from one prayer house to another.
Could you tell us the reason why you were going from one prayer house to another
and what was your impression right at that point in time?
The thing that was surprising to me was that
even when you were reading the Bible in the house, she would tell you, "Don't read that book here.
I don't want you to read that book. Is that the only book you can read in this house?"
If you took her to church, she didn't want to go to church.
"Come and let's pray." - "No."
You said you took her from one prayer house to another.
Could you tell us - what was your impression about your step-daughter?
From what the men of God were saying, the impression was that the baby is possessed.
So I don't hide anything from my husband.
I came and told my husband, "Please, this is what I've been told. This is what is happening.
So what do you think?".
There were times that even when I pointed out something that was not right with the child,
my husband would get so angry with me that he would not talk to me for two weeks.
Ok. Finally, you are here in The SCOAN. What do you want now?
What is want is that the man of God should say something about the baby and our marriage
because I'm here for the man of God to help me.
This man wants me out of his house.
Ok. Let's hear from your husband.
Mr & Mrs Helms Atud & Family - Prophecy Confirmation
Thank you very much.
Good morning everybody!
My name is Helms Atud.
I'm a Cameroonian living in Namibia with my family.
This is my wife Chakoi.
This is my daughter from another relationship that didn't go well.
When the child was ten months old, the mother tried to commit suicide and abandoned the baby.
The government gave this baby to me.
Later on, I had full custody of the child.
I have been living with her since the age of ten months.
That is our son Helms Junior, and my mother-in-law Katrine.
When we were here on last Sunday,
I was one of the first people the Spirit of God located through the man of God, Prophet T.B. Joshua.
I was seated right over there. He came to me and said, "How are you, sir?"
I said, "I'm fine". He asked, "Where is your wife?"
I said, "There is my wife". He said, "There is a problem in your home.
For the past three months, you have been living like cat and mouse at home.
There is no peace in your home.
Your wife loves you. This is a woman God has given you but there is no affection from your side".
And he asked me to try and help my wife.
Those were the prophecies, and I confirm these prophecies to be true.
As my wife said, three months ago we had an argument
and I told her if we cannot solve this problem in our home, I cannot live like this anymore.
That was in August. And I told her very clearly that there is August, September, October.
By the end of October, if we cannot find a solution, I will be renting an apartment
and she will go and stay with the little boy and I will stay with the girl in the house.
How did this come about?
When my wife came from Cameroon,
I had already explained the situation of this little girl to her in Cameroon.
So when she moved over and we got married, we were living happily.
It was just honeymoon, seriously.
Six, seven, eight months down the road, my wife was not getting pregnant.
She started getting very worried.
She started praying, fasting for seven days.
I have never seen it; seven days, day and night, she would eat and drink nothing,
just praying for the fruit of the womb.
I told her that God will give us a child at His own time.
That did not end there.
My wife now started praying with a lot of pastors - too many pastors.
They were giving too many revelations.
One of the revelations was: The reason she was not conceiving is because this child is possessed.
Now, this is a child I had been living with since ten months.
I didn't know anything about that.
I said, "Fine. Tell the pastor to come to our house.
As we see on Emmanuel TV, when somebody is possessed, they deliver the person".
This pastor came, stayed with us, asked me to get salt, olive oil and a breakable plate.
That they will do deliverance in the middle of the night.
He came in the middle of the night and did the deliverance.
To be honest, I thought that was it.
The pastor left and went back the next day.
But this problem still continued.
At that point now, there was tension between my wife and the little girl,
and it was creating a distance.
Three or four months went by.
Still prayer, fasting, prophecies, revelations - it was every day.
One morning my wife got up and said to me that she couldn't find her wedding ring.
She went to bed with the wedding ring but now she cannot find it.
It has been removed from her hand. I said, "What do you mean?
You might have forgotten it in the bedroom. Just check around".
A prophecy came from that situation
that the little child is possessed and is fighting the marriage.
That's why we were in that situation.
Then now I said, "Ok, fine. Let's go to church. Let's go to your church".
We went to her church and met the pastors.
They prayed and delivered the child.
We went back home.
The situation was not changing.
I got confused. This girl, at this age - she was just about four then, and depression had kicked in.
She was on depression medication.
I was like, "No. A child at this age cannot be on depression medication".
The child was by herself, my wife was by herself.
When I came home, I was confused, I didn't know what to do.
I love my wife, I love my daughter.
I found myself in the middle; I didn't know what to do.
I just said to myself, "She is praying every day. God will definitely answer her prayers
and she will get pregnant".
We lived like that; no happiness.
Three or four months down the line, my wife told me she was pregnant.
I was celebrating. I said, "This is the end of our problem".
No, this was not the end of our problem.
Now, she got pregnant.
I thought the distance would close.
The problem would get solved but the problem didn't get solved.
At that point now, it got worse.
I only heard this story she explained about her reason for not taking the child to school
whilst being at The SCOAN and we are living together
and this has been going on for more than a year.
So she stopped taking the child to school.
We are blessed; we have a lot of cars.
She drives; she is at home studying for her Master's degree programme in public health.
As she studies, she stays at home; she is not working.
So she normally takes the child to school; they go to church together.
Now, she stopped taking the child to school, stopped taking the child to church.
The nanny is the one - she gives the nanny taxi money to take the child.
The school is a five minutes drive from our home - five minutes.
On Sundays she goes to church; the nanny takes the child to church.
I looked at the situation and said, "Fine. She is a pregnant lady. Let me just leave it".
They say that when a lady is pregnant, her attitude, her behaviour, everything changes.
I left it at that point.
But it went on and on.
I got up one morning and said to her, "I don't know what is happening.
Where is that beautiful, loving, God-fearing lady I got married to?
How can you be so bitter? Even to take a child to school?
I don't care whether the child is possessed or not.
This is a child God has given me. That is my cross but I give her my life.
And I'm seeing you, you cannot just take this child to school.
If I'm dead, will you pay her school fees?" That is what I asked her.
No reaction came from my wife and honestly, that moment everything died within me.
I just decided, "Fine. I will just wait for her to give birth.
I will see how the situation will go".
She gave birth.
I was hoping now that she had given birth to a child.
Maybe she will understand how I feel towards this child,
now that she has a child of her own.
That was my thinking.
But it still didn't get any better.
It just didn't get any better.
The distance was just there; my wife wanted nothing to do with the child.
We were living together in a house - there is no happiness, love, togetherness.
I was confused; I didn't know what to do.
At that moment I just made a decision,
"My wife is studying; I cannot live with this situation anymore".
It has given me so much stress, my BP has gone so high,
I'm already on BP medication.
I even left my house one morning so confused and stressed,
drove my car into the street and an oncoming car hit me
Luckily it was a small taxi - I was driving a landcruiser -
it hit the car - it wasn't driving too fast; nobody was hurt.
I just apologised; my insurance took care of everything.
At that point, I started thinking that I can't live like this anymore.
I really didn't know what I had to do.
I made a promise to myself that I will make sure that my wife finishes her studies,
and make sure she gets a good job.
I started talking to my friends in her field,
"You are in public health, my wife is not in public health. Please, I want her--".
So we already started that process.
In my mind, I was thinking that when she gets a job, she will be settled,
find her an apartment, I put her there with the child,
we try to live apart, I see whether that works.
That was what I was thinking and I made up my mind, quietly within me.
We were just living with no love, no happiness, no affection, nothing.
Even in the midst of this challenge of your biological daughter being alleged as a witch,
and you were still trying to make preparations for your wife to get a job after her studies.
Yes, because that is our son.
If I'm not there tomorrow, I want to know that my wife is in a situation
where she can take care of our son.
That is what I was thinking to myself.
Now, with that mindset, I just decided to leave that situation at that point.
Three months ago, as the man of God rightly said--
My doctor is also a family friend. They have three daughters - friends of hers.
So when I went to my doctor that my medication was not working.
My BP was still high; I was having a lot of headache.
She should please do something about it.
She changed my medication.
Then she said to me, "But it is weekend. Why don't you send Emma over to spend time with the girls?"
I said, "It is fine. I will drop Emma over on Friday".
Going to pick Emma now, they called me on the side, "What is going on in your home, Helms?"
Who is Emma?
Emma is my daughter - this one.
I dropped her over at the doctor's house.
The husband is a medical doctor, the wife is a medical doctor,
the husband is a Cameroonian as well, living in Namibia.
We are in a Cameroonian community, we socialise in that way.
So I dropped Emma over.
Now going to get Emma, the husband asked me, "Helms, what is going on in your house?
As a medical doctor, I will speak. I don't really want to get involved in your family issue.
But this child is very depressed.
This child is very depressed and she is refusing to go back home.
Because I've been trying to take her back home, she is crying and refusing.
She doesn't want to go back home, that she is not happy".
Upon hearing this, I became very sad and angry.
I took Emma home, called my wife and told her,
"See, we have two kids.
We cannot have this girl and the little boy in the same house as parents,
and one is getting all the love, all the affection and all the attention
and the other is getting nothing.
So this situation already got me so stressed up.
I can't take it anymore.
This is August.
August, September, October - three months.
Within these three months, find a way to see how we can live in this house as a family".
That is what I told my wife. "If not, that's it!
We are going apart. I will find an apartment for you".
What I was planning to do after, I decided of doing it now
because I just couldn't take it anymore.
And this is in accordance with the three months the man of God, Prophet T.B. Joshua, mentioned.
Exactly.
Seriously, our journey of coming here has been too long.
It has been two years of pain, two years of frustration, two years of unhappiness.
Still it was a challenge coming to The SCOAN.
So when I said that now to my wife, a couple of days later she went to see her pastor.
Her pastor called me. I think she explained the situation, what I had told her, that we are going apart.
Her pastor called me and said, "Your wife told me this problem you guys are having at home
concerning this child".
I said to him, "Pastor, I'm in your church, my wife fellowships there.
We've been bringing this problem here for over a year.
If there is no solution, what do you want me to do?
If not, to just separate them apart because I cannot take it.
You are a pastor, pray and deliver her".
The pastor said to me, "No, it is not that I cannot pray and deliver this child.
It is that too many other pastors have spoken
and your wife is dead convinced that the child is possessed".
So he didn't want to say anything because it would be controversial.
So he then said to me that the coordinators in Namibia who coordinate for people to come to The SCOAN
were coming to his church in the next 30 minutes.
That is the only place he believed I could go to.
And the only man of God he believed that could speak peace and happiness
into my family, is Prophet T.B. Joshua.
You mean, this was a recommendation given by the pastor in Namibia?
This is what the senior pastor of my church told me.
He also came to The SCOAN; he was there last week.
He said, "I'm going to The SCOAN.
Prophet T.B. Joshua is my holy father.
So, I'm going to The SCOAN.
The people organising the trip are coming to my office.
So if you can afford it, please that is the only place I know
were you can go to and you will have peace at home.
Because once Prophet T.B. Joshua speaks, he will deliver your family.
So that is why I came here.
Once I walked into the church and was given a seat, I was just praying to myself,
"Lord, let the man of God locate us.
We cannot come here and go back because this is our last bus stop".
That was my prayer.
I was one of the first people he located.
So I'm here trusting that whilst we are here speaking, this problem is finished.
We go back a happy family.
I love my wife. I love my daughter. But I just don't know to which side to go.
I cannot take sides, I just cannot take sides.
Even coming here, the day before we started our journey,
a good family friend called me in the morning and asked, "Where are you, Helms?"
I said, "I'm on my way to work".
She asked whether I had gone far.
I said, "Yes, I left early because I have a very long day
because I'm travelling out of the country tomorrow".
She said, "Please come. I need to see you.
I have a message for you. I was praying and the Holy Spirit gave me a message for you".
I said, "Holy Spirit! Fine, I'm coming.
If I cannot make it during the day, I will come at the end of the day on my way home".
So I couldn't make it during the day.
At the end of the day, around 9pm on my way home, I stopped at her house.
She told me that she was praying and the Holy Spirit gave her a revelation
that we shouldn't go to The SCOAN, we shouldn't go to Nigeria.
We will not find a solution there. We should rather go to South Africa for prayers.
Ok. We all know that God is able to do all things.
In the midst of this confusion, you found your way to The SCOAN, the arena of liberty.
What do you now want to hear from the man of God?
I second what my wife said. I want the man of God to speak on this child and our marriage.
That is all I came here for and that is what I'm praying for.
Thank you very much.
Let's hear from our mother.
Emmanuel! (God with us - Matthew 1:23)
My name is Mrs Katrine Chakoi. I'm a Cameroonian.
This is my son-in-law. His name is Mr Helms.
This is my daughter. Her name is Chakoi.
This is her son. His name is Helms Junior.
This is her step-daughter. Her name is Emma.
Ok, because of time. If we gave you time to explain, we would not be able to leave here today.
And the man of God, Prophet T.B. Joshua, is eager to come into our midst.
But before then, I hope you are happy that your daughter and your son-in-law are here
to hear God's opinion about this marriage.
In fact, I'm very happy because when I went to Namibia,
I saw them living as strangers in the same house, like cats and dogs.
Thank you very much.
To God be the glory. We believe that both of you have taken the right decision
to come to The SCOAN to hear God's opinion about this marriage
and the impression of your daughter all over Namibia, to be precise.
We believe God that at the moment the man of God, Prophet T.B. Joshua, comes out into our midst,
let's believe God that definitely, we are going to hear God's opinion from him.
God bless you and thank You, Jesus, for this opportunity.
Let's put our hands together beautifully for the miracle-working God!
After Mr and Mrs Helms Atud had share their emotional pain and offence that had shaken their marriage,
Prophet T.B. Joshua came into their midst and spoke the mind of God
concerning their family and the little girl concerned.
Surely, the right knowledge of God settles peace.
Let me talk to my mummy here. Come on!
I was listening to your testimony, your issue
concerning the disagreement, the fight between you and your wife and all other.
I learnt that the whole fight is about our little baby here.
That she is a witch, she is not a witch, isn't it?
That's true, Man of God.
I would like to hear from my sister, not you.
Let me hear from my sister. Feel free to talk. I just have one minute for you.
Yes. Actually, when I came to live with my husband,
I noticed some kind of abnormalities with the baby.
The baby would not like us to have prayers in the house.
She was rejecting a lot of things concerning Christianity.
Ok, simple. We learnt that a lot of prophets and men of God have given that message
that this lady is a witch.
That she is possessed.
Ok. What is your decision?
Do you see any sign that she is possessed?
Well, she doesn't like going to church, prayers in the house.
She just rejects all of these things.
Ok, it's alright. Thank you.
Yes, Man of God.
A lot of prophets have convinced my wife that the child is possessed,
and that is why we are here.
Ok. Did your husband let you know that he has a baby at home before you married him?
Yes, he told me; I knew.
And you knew the baby before you married your husband?
Yes, I knew.
So, if I may just put it this way:
Since you chose to marry your husband and you knew this baby before you married your husband,
and your husband never hid this baby from you, he never?
Yes, he never did.
Ok. That is to show that whether the lady is a witch or not, and you know the baby,
and you were able to marry your husband with the witch,
why do you get to the house and you don't want that witch?
No, take it.
So can we say, when you married your husband,
that is when the witch possessed that lady?
You know, probably, at the time you later married your husband,
the witch possessed that girl.
Because you didn't see the lady as a witch before you married your husband.
Because I want to believe that if you knew that the lady was a witch,
you probably may not have married this man. Can you answer the question?
I came and met her in my husband's house.
But you told me that when you were outside and about to marry this man,
he told you that he has a baby.
Yes, he told me that he had a baby. So I came and I was staying with the baby.
It was during the time that I was staying with the baby---
Take it easy.
The question - you knew this baby, this little girl before you married your husband,
before you finally came to the house?
Yes, I did.
Ok. Did you see her as a witch?
No.
Ok, it was when you married the man, the girl became a witch.
Yes, when I later noticed it.
No, wait. It was when you came to the house, you later realised that the girl is a witch.
Yes, I later--
Wait.
What I'm saying:
Before you came to the house, the lady was not a witch.
Yes.
Ok. It was when you came to the house and became a wife,
you later realised that the baby--
Yes.
Aha. Ok.
So this means this child was not a witch before you married her dad.
No.
Ok. So it means it must be you and your husband that possessed this girl
because it must be you and your husband that possessed this girl.
So if this girl is a witch, it means you are the biggest witch and your husband is the biggest wizard.
So it is a shameful thing to tell the world that she is a witch
when you never saw this girl as a witch before you married the father.
And it was when you got to the house that you realised she is a witch.
It means it is either you or your husband that possessed this girl.
My sister, I just want you to learn this wisdom.
This girl is not a witch at all.
And two:
I want to salute you.
Because if you didn't love this man, if you wanted to leave, you wouldn't need to come here.
It means the love is there.
There are some people out there that are deceiving.
They deceived your spirit
because you regard them as men of God or women of God.
Never to blame you at all; you have no blame.
So I want to say, you are a good woman.
Why?
Because for you to come here and for you to be open,
and you really want to know who this girl is,
I want to salute you. Thank you very much.
So she has no blame at all because she is very thorough.
They say, find out the truth and the truth will set you free.
She tried to find out the truth.
If she were wicked, she would have harmed this girl.
But she never harmed her.
You know the way and manner people behave to witches and wizards
when they know a baby is a witch. They can even kill the girl.
They can even poison the girl. They can even do any evil to that girl.
But she is not interested in that.
She just wants to ask from God.
She never said she is the one who killed her witch.
She said some people say she is a witch. It is not her fault.
And I want to thank you too for also persevering, trying to know the truth.
This woman loves you.
If you leave this woman, you will leave your destined wife.
I know she loves me; I know.
But this issue has caused a lot of distance between us, Man of God.
That is why we are here.
Do you know that what happened now will strengthen your marriage.
Definitely, Man of God.
And it will make your marriage mature.
Thank you, Man of God. Thank you very much.
So you will see that this woman is a mother and you are a father.
So you people have passed a test in marriage
Thank you, Man of God. Amen.
Can you give a hug to your husband? Thank you.
Thank you, Man of God.
Thank you very much. Thank you.
Thank you. I will see you.
So, madam, you will be my guest. After the service I want to see you.
Thank you.
The SCOAN Sunday Service